Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today we're bringing you a lesson that was requested by one of our listeners.
今天我们带来了一节课，是由一位听众请求的。
Yes, that's right.
是的，没错。
We got a request for a dialogue about a receptionist.
我们收到了一个关于前台对话的请求。
So a receptionist at an office or at a hotel.
所以是办公室或酒店的前台。
So today's dialogue is simple but we're going to be looking at some really great phrases.
今天的对话很简单，但我们会看一些非常棒的短语。
Yeah, phrases that will help you sound really, really professional and really fluent.
是的，这些短语能让你听起来非常专业、非常流利。
So we are at an office today and the receptionist is greeting somebody that has an appointment.
今天我们在一间办公室，前台正在迎接一位有预约的人。
All right, let's see what happens.
好了，我们来看看发生了什么。
Good afternoon.
下午好。
May I help you?
有什么可以帮您的吗？
Yes, I'm here to see Joanna Stevens.
是的，我来找Joanna Stevens。
I have an appointment at four.
我四点钟有预约。
Certainly.
当然可以。
May I take your name?
请问您贵姓？
I'll let her know you've arrived.
我会告诉她您已经到了。
Sure.
好的。
It's Josh O'Neill.
我叫Josh O'Neill。
Miss Stevens will be with you momentarily.
Stevens小姐马上就来见您。
Can I offer you something to drink?
需要给您来点喝的吗？
Yes, coffee would be nice.
好的，咖啡就好。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Here you are.
给您。
Miss Stevens is ready for you now.
Stevens小姐现在可以见您了。
I'll show you to her office right this way.
我带您去她的办公室，这边请。
Just watch your step here.
小心脚下。
Well that's pretty embarrassing, hey?
嗯，那挺尴尬的，是吧？
That was embarrassing.
那真尴尬。
That's what happens to women when they wear high heels, see?
这就是女人穿高跟鞋的下场，看到了吧？
Actually that happened to me last weekend.
其实上周末我也遇到了这种事。
Really?
真的吗？
I fell down the stairs and my knees are quite blue.
我从楼梯上摔下来，膝盖都青了。
Oh no, see?
哦不，看到了吧？
High heels are dangerous.
高跟鞋很危险。
I don't know why women wear them.
我不知道女人为什么穿它们。
Well, I don't know, but that's not what we're here to discover.
嗯，我不知道，但这不是我们今天要探讨的。
Right.
对。
Okay, so let's take a look at some of these great phrases in Fluency Builder.
好的，那我们来看看流利度构建器里的一些好短语。
I really liked how this receptionist used some excellent phrases to sound really professional.
我真的很喜欢这位前台用了一些很棒的短语，听起来非常专业。
One thing she said was, certainly.
她说的一句话是：certainly。
Certainly.
Certainly。
So why did she say certainly?
那她为什么说certainly呢？
Well this is a nice way to respond, to make the other person know that you understand
这是一种很好的回应方式，让对方知道你理解
what they said.
他们说的话。
So Josh O'Neil said, yes, I'm here to see you Joanna Stevens.
所以Josh O'Neil说：是的，我来找Joanna Stevens。
I have an appointment at four.
我四点钟有预约。
Certainly.
当然可以。
So she is saying, I understand what you said.
所以她是在说：我理解你说的话。
Yes.
是的。
So she said, may I take your name?
然后她说：may I take your name?
May I take your name?
So this is a nice way of saying, what is your name?
这是一种很好的方式，相当于问：你叫什么名字？
Yeah.
是的。
So, now this is really important because if you said, what is your name?
这很重要，因为如果你说：你叫什么名字？
Is that correct?
那对吗？
It's correct, but it's not really very...
是对的，但不太……
Exactly.
正是。
Or I would say polite to a certain extent.
或者说在某种程度上不太礼貌。
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So may I take your name?
所以是：may I take your name?
May I take your name?
So you use this phrase when you are going to write down the person's name.
当你打算记下对方名字时，就用这个短语。
Right.
对。
So if you meet somebody on the street or at a bar, you wouldn't say, may I take your name?
如果你在街上或酒吧遇到某人，你不会说：may I take your name?
No.
不会。
Right.
对。
Unless you're going to write it down.
除非你要记下来。
So usually for an office setting where the receptionist has to write down the name.
所以通常是在办公室场景，前台需要记下名字。
Yes.
是的。
Alright, one more phrase.
好了，还有一个短语。
Ms. Stevens will be with you momentarily.
Stevens小姐马上就来见您。
Okay.
好的。
So, Ms. Stevens will be with you momentarily.
所以是：Ms. Stevens will be with you momentarily.
Will be with you momentarily.
Okay, so this is really polite.
好的，这非常礼貌。
Yes.
是的。
Momentarily, what does that mean?
Momentarily，那是什么意思？
In a moment.
马上。
Soon.
很快。
Again, she could have said, Ms. Stevens will come out soon or Ms. Stevens will see you
同样，她本可以说：Stevens小姐很快就出来，或者Stevens小姐
in a minute.
一会儿见你。
Yes.
是的。
But that's, again, it's not really that polite, right?
但那又不太礼貌，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
So if you want to be formal, you can say, Ms. Stevens will be with you momentarily.
所以如果你想正式一点，可以说：Ms. Stevens will be with you momentarily.
Okay.
好的。
That's a really nice phrase.
那是个很好的短语。
Alright, there's so much in this dialogue.
好的，这个对话里有很多内容。
So many great, wonderful, polite phrases.
这么多精彩、礼貌的短语。
So why don't we listen to it one more time, but this time, slowed down.
那我们再听一遍吧，但这次慢速播放。
Good afternoon.
下午好。
May I help you?
有什么可以帮您的吗？
Yes, I'm here to see Joanna Stevens.
是的，我来找Joanna Stevens。
I have an appointment at four.
我四点钟有预约。
Certainly.
当然可以。
May I take your name?
请问您贵姓？
I'll let her know you've arrived.
我会告诉她您已经到了。
Sure.
好的。
It's Josh O'Neil.
我叫Josh O'Neil。
Ms. Stevens will be with you momentarily.
Stevens小姐马上就来见您。
Can I offer you something to drink?
需要给您来点喝的吗？
Yes, coffee would be nice.
好的，咖啡就好。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Here you are.
给您。
Ms. Stevens is ready for you now.
Stevens小姐现在可以见您了。
I'll show you to her office.
我带您去她的办公室。
Right this way.
这边请。
Just watch your step here.
小心脚下。
Okay, so it's pretty clear now, but there are still a couple of phrases that I would
好的，现在很清楚了，但我还想
like to look at.
再看几个短语。
So why don't we look at the last two sentences?
那我们看看最后两句话吧。
Okay.
好的。
Ms. Stevens is ready for you now.
Stevens小姐现在可以见您了。
Ms. Stevens is ready for you.
So when she says ready for you, what does that mean?
当她说ready for you时，那是什么意思？
Prepared to speak to you.
准备好和你谈话。
Okay.
好的。
So instead of saying Ms. Stevens is ready or Ms. Stevens can see you now, you use this
所以不说Stevens小姐准备好了或Stevens小姐现在可以见你，而是用这个
great little phrase, is ready for you.
很棒的小短语：is ready for you。
Okay.
好的。
And then she said I'll show you to her office.
然后她说：I'll show you to her office.
I'll show you to her office.
This is a lovely way of saying I will take you to the office.
这是一种可爱的说法，相当于：我带你去办公室。
I will take you to the office.
我带你去办公室。
And she followed it by saying right this way.
然后她接着说：right this way。
Right this way.
Right this way。
So again, walk this way.
所以又是：走这边。
Walk this way.
走这边。
This way, please.
这边请。
Yes.
是的。
Right this way.
这边请。
It sounds really, really nice, really polite, really welcoming.
听起来非常好，非常礼貌，非常热情。
Right.
对。
And especially if you use it together, right?
尤其是如果你把它们连起来用，对吧？
I'll show you to her office right this way, please.
我带您去她的办公室，这边请。
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So it's a really great way of being polite to somebody at an office.
所以这是在办公室对别人礼貌的一种很好的方式。
Now the final useful phrase, watch your step.
现在最后一个有用的短语：watch your step。
Watch your step.
Watch your step。
So watch your step.
所以是watch your step。
You see that everywhere in science.
你在科学领域到处都能看到。
Be careful.
小心。
Be careful where you step.
小心脚下。
Yes.
是的。
Be careful where you're walking.
小心你走路的地方。
Okay.
好的。
So obviously she didn't watch her step and she fell.
所以显然她没注意脚下，摔倒了。
She fell.
她摔倒了。
Okay.
好的。
So really great phrases.
所以真是很棒的短语。
Let's listen to this dialogue one last time.
我们最后再听一遍这个对话。
Good afternoon.
下午好。
May I help you?
有什么可以帮您的吗？
Yes.
是的。
I'm here to see Joanna Stevens.
我来找Joanna Stevens。
I have an appointment at four.
我四点钟有预约。
Certainly.
当然可以。
May I take your name?
请问您贵姓？
I'll let her know you've arrived.
我会告诉她您已经到了。
Sure.
好的。
It's Josh O'Neill.
我叫Josh O'Neill。
Miss Stevens will be with you momentarily.
Stevens小姐马上就来见您。
Can I offer you something to drink?
需要给您来点喝的吗？
Yes.
好的。
Coffee would be nice.
咖啡就好。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Here you are.
给您。
Miss Stevens is ready for you now.
Stevens小姐现在可以见您了。
I'll show you to her office right this way.
我带您去她的办公室，这边请。
Just watch your step here.
小心脚下。
Alright so a really simple dialogue but with a lot of good phrases in there and it's also
好的，一个很简单的对话，但里面有很多好短语，而且对
a good review for more advanced students, right?
更高级的学生来说也是个很好的复习，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
Remember like these phrases can really help you sound more professional, more welcoming,
记住，这些短语真的能让你听起来更专业、更热情、
more polite basically.
更礼貌。
Okay.
好的。
So if you have any questions or doubts, please come to our website EnglishPod.com.
如果你有任何问题或疑问，请访问我们的网站EnglishPod.com。
And Marco and I are always around to respond to your questions and comments.
Marco和我随时都在，回答你们的问题和评论。
Okay guys.
好了，各位。
So we'll see you there and until next time it's goodbye.
我们那里见，下次再见，拜拜。